export const promptResponseData = [
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Save More Money?",
      "Response": "A budget can help you save money, but many people won't use one if it feels difficult, dull or restrictive. Here's how to\nmake budgeting and saving easy and empowering.\nFirst, play detective by tracking your income and expenses for 30 days—an app can save time here. Next, use the\nresults to set up a budget that fits your goals and your daily routine. For example, if your month of tracking reveals\nyou're spending more than you want on dining out, set a monthly ceiling. Then, before you order takeout, check your\nspending so you stay on budget. You don't have to completely revamp your spending in one month. Use your tracking data to identify changes that feel\neasy, and implement them one at a time. This way, you'll boost your savings balance without feeling overwhelmed or\ndeprived. Adding a \"cheat day\" category to your budget can also give you a little wiggle room for expenses during\nthose extra-hard day.Accelerate your progress by bucketing—automatically depositing money in separate accounts, each designated\nfor a key goal. You'll save time and stay on track because once you've set up the automatic deposit, you don't have to\ndo a thing."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Improve My Credit Score?",
      "Response": "Improving your credit history and score can take time, but better credit can help you save money on mortgages, auto loans and even insurance. A few important steps you can take to improve your credit are: • Make on-time payments: A record of on-time payments can help your credit, and missing a payment or having accounts sent to collections can hurt it. • Don't max out credit cards: Try to use just a small portion of your available credit limits on revolving credit accounts, such as credit cards and lines of credit. The people with the best credit scores tend to have utilization ratios under 10%. For example, if their combined credit limits are $10,000, they'd have a combined credit card balance that's under $1,000. But you don't need to revolve a balance—that's a potentially costly myth. Try to pay the bill in full every month to avoid interest. • Use varying types of credit: Responsibly managing open installment loans and revolving credit accounts can help your credit scores. Having a good payment history with a specific type of loan, such as an auto loan, can also be important if you're applying for a new loan of the same type. • Have a long credit history: The age of your oldest and newest accounts—and the average age of all the accounts in your credit report—can affect your scores. Both open and closed accounts can count toward the average age of your accounts, which you can calculate by adding up the age of each account and dividing by the number of accounts. You can increase the average age of your accounts by (sparingly) opening new accounts. • Don't apply for new credit too often: Applying for new credit accounts can lead to a hard inquiry—when lenders thoroughly review your credit before making a decision. These can have small negative effects on your credit score. • Review your credit reports: Check your credit reports for errors that might be hurting your scores. You can dispute these errors with the creditors or credit bureaus. Lenders can choose from different types of credit scores, which is why you might find that you have varying scores depending on where you check your score. However, most credit scores are based on the same underlying information in one of your credit reports. As a result, some of the basic actions—like making payments on time and using a small portion of your credit limits—can help all of your credit scores."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Much Do I Need to Save for Retirement?",
      "Response": "You don't have to spend hours crunching numbers to get a useful estimate of how much money you'll need to retire (but you can if you want to!). Start with two easy-to-remember rules: the 25x rule and the 4% rule. They're very similar math-wise, but each offers a different perspective on retirement saving and spending. The 25x rule The 25x rule gives you a baseline retirement savings goal. Simply: • Estimate your annual spending amount by multiplying the average of your monthly expenses by 12 and adding in\nless-frequent purchases, such as biannual insurance premiums and annual vehicle registration fees.\n• Multiply your annual spending by 25.\nFor example, if you spend about $42,000 a year, multiply that by 25 to get $1.05 million. Take that number and refine it\nbased on your retirement lifestyle preferences and other factors.\nThe 4% rule\nThe 4% rule states that you can withdraw 4% of your retirement savings each year, and your portfolio could last about\n30 years. You can use this rule once you retire and as part of your planning. For example, say you now spend about\n$4,500 a month, but you plan to spend $5,000 a month in retirement. That's $60,000 a year. Divide $60,000 by .04 to\nget $1.5 million. (Alternatively, multiply by 25 to get the same result.) You can use that as an investment goal."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Choose a Bank for My Savings Account?",
      "Response": "First, look for a bank that's FDIC-insured, such as Synchrony Bank, so your savings (up to $250,000 per account holder, ownership category, per FDIC-insured bank) are protected even if the bank fails. Though bank failures are rare, it's essential to protect yourself. Next, find a bank that charges few fees and has little or no minimum balance requirements. Seek out the most competitive interest rate for your money. Consider your needs: if you want convenience and higher interest rates, consider an online-only bank that offers cash access through ATMs."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Are Online Banks Safe?",
      "Response": "As long as an online bank is FDIC-insured, your money is generally safe. Online banks typically offer higher interest rates than traditional banks. Look for security features such as multifactor authentication (preferably not based on text messages), and practice safe online habits: avoid using public devices or networks to sign into your account, use a strong password exclusive to that account, and learn to avoid phishing."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Much Do I Need to Save for College?",
      "Response": "Based on recent CollegeBoard data, the average price for tuition and fees ranges from $10,950 at a public four-year in-state school to $39,400 at a private nonprofit four-year school for the 2022-2023 school year. To estimate future costs, consider projections and calculate how many years until your child starts college. Start saving early, even small amounts each month. Use high yield savings accounts or a 529 plan. Note that most students receive financial aid that reduces the total cost. Use the school's net price calculator for an estimate of actual costs."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Save for a House?",
      "Response": "To save for a down payment, use budgeting and bucketing strategies. Consider the type of mortgage and the size of the down payment. While a 20% down payment can qualify you for a lower interest rate or avoid extra costs, you may qualify for mortgages with lower or no down payment requirements. Factors like monthly costs, long-term costs, duration of stay, and potential refinancing can influence mortgage choice. For interim savings, consider high yield savings accounts, money market accounts, and certificates of deposit (CDs) for low-risk returns."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Set Up a Savings Account for My Child?",
      "Response": "You can open a savings account for your child as soon as they have a Social Security number. Options include a custodial account or a joint savings account. With a custodial account, you manage the account and your child cannot conduct transactions without you. A joint account allows your child more independence, potentially including the use of a debit card. Identification and an initial deposit are required to open the account."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What Is a Good Age for Kids to Learn About Money?",
      "Response": "Start teaching kids about money as early as age 3 with concepts like delayed gratification and the value of work. Use storybooks to present ideas in relatable ways and make learning about money a game. As they grow, incorporate money discussions into daily life: point out prices while shopping, provide an allowance and help them manage it, open a joint savings account, and involve them in the process. By their teenage years, introduce goal setting, part-time jobs, and even credit to help them understand how to reach their financial goals."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What Is the Best Way to Borrow Money?",
      "Response": "Understand the loan terms, including monthly repayments, potential changes over time, and consequences of non-repayment. Choose a loan or line of credit that fits your needs. Financing options include installment loans (e.g., student loans, auto loans) and revolving accounts (e.g., credit cards, personal lines of credit). Secured loans require collateral but may offer lower interest rates, while unsecured loans don't require collateral but can have higher interest rates."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Do I Finance a Big Purchase?",
      "Response": "Use personal loans, credit cards, or buy now, pay later (BNPL) plans for consumer products, often with no fees or interest. For larger purchases like vehicles or homes, consider secured loans (auto loans, mortgages) which offer favorable terms. Always review the financing terms carefully."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What's the Best Way to Invest My Money?",
      "Response": "Assess your risk tolerance, time horizon, and reaction to potential losses. For short-term investments, choose safer options. For long-term investments, consider higher-risk opportunities for greater returns. Diversify investments to reduce risk, though it can't be eliminated completely. For short-term savings, consider high yield savings accounts and certificates of deposit (CDs)."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Can I Get Out of Debt?",
      "Response": "Reduce expenses or increase income to pay down debt. Use strategies like the avalanche (paying off highest-interest debt first) or snowball (paying off smallest debts first) methods. Refinance or restructure debts to lower interest rates using personal loans or balance transfer credit cards. Combining multiple approaches may expedite debt repayment. Improved credit scores from paying down debts can help secure better loan terms for remaining debts."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is Renting or Buying a Home Better?",
      "Response": "Renting is maintenance-free and avoids property expenses like taxes but may involve rent increases and restrictions. Buying offers freedom to personalize and potential property value appreciation but includes maintenance and property tax responsibilities. Consider factors like duration of stay and space needs. Use a rent vs. buy calculator for financial comparison."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How Can I Start a Savings Plan?",
      "Response": "Track income and expenses, creating buckets for different savings goals. Prioritize savings over discretionary spending. Automate transfers to savings accounts. Adjust the plan as needed based on realistic expectations. Use a savings goal calculator to estimate timelines for achieving goals."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "PM CARES Fund is a public charitable trust established to provide relief in emergency or distress situations, like the COVID-19 pandemic. It aims to support public health emergencies and other types of calamities by funding healthcare facilities, relevant research, and necessary infrastructure."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who are the Trustees and Advisors of the PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "The Prime Minister of India is the Chairperson (ex-officio). Ex-officio Trustees include the Minister of Defence, Minister of Home Affairs, and Minister of Finance. Additional trustees are Shri Justice K.T. Thomas (Retd.), Shri Kariya Munda, and Shri Ratan N. Tata. Advisors include Shri Rajiv Mehrishi, Smt. Sudha Murthy, and Shri Anand Shah."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the Objectives of the PM CARES Fund Trust?",
      "Response": "The objectives include supporting relief efforts during public health or other emergencies, providing financial assistance to affected populations, and upgrading healthcare facilities and infrastructure. The Fund may also undertake any activity consistent with these goals."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is the legal framework of PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "PM CARES Fund is registered as a Public Charitable Trust under the Registration Act, 1908, in New Delhi on March 27, 2020."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the responsibilities of the Trustees?",
      "Response": "Trustees are responsible for fulfilling the Trust's objectives, managing contributions, ensuring proper application of funds, and preparing necessary legal filings, accounts, and returns."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How is the PM CARES Fund administered?",
      "Response": "The Fund is administered by an honorary Additional Secretary/Joint Secretary in the PMO, assisted by other designated officers. The Prime Minister's Office provides administrative and secretarial support as needed by the Trustees."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Where is the Head Office of the Fund?",
      "Response": "The Head Office of the Fund is in the Prime Minister’s Office, South Block, New Delhi."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What type of domestic donations are accepted in PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "The Fund accepts voluntary contributions from individuals and organizations, including CSR contributions from companies and PSUs. However, budgetary sources from PSUs are not accepted."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the modes through which domestic donation can be made?",
      "Response": "Donations can be made via Net Banking, Card Payments, other payment modes like NEFT/RTGS, or directly at SBI branches. Online contributions can be made through pmcares.gov.in, pmindia.gov.in, or bank portals. Cheques or demand drafts can be sent to the Under Secretary (Funds) at the PMO."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Are contributions towards the PM CARES Fund exempted from Income Tax?",
      "Response": "Yes, donations to the PM CARES Fund are deductible under Section 80(G) of the Income Tax Act, 1961, for those opting for the old tax slabs. The deduction is based on the claim made in the return of income; Form No. 10BE is not required for PM CARES Fund."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is PM CARES Fund exempted from paying Income Tax?",
      "Response": "Yes, the Fund is exempted from paying Income Tax under Section 10(23)(c) of the Income Tax Act, 1961."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Does contribution towards PM CARES Fund qualify as CSR expenditure?",
      "Response": "Yes, contributions to the PM CARES Fund qualify as CSR expenditure under the Companies Act, 2013."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Does PM CARES Fund have a Permanent Account Number (PAN)?",
      "Response": "Yes, the PAN for PM CARES Fund is AAETP3993P."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who has the powers to formulate criteria for disbursal of funds?",
      "Response": "The Trustees of the PM CARES Fund have the authority to formulate rules and criteria for disbursing funds."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is the quantum of funds collected and sanctioned?",
      "Response": "Details on the funds collected and sanctioned can be found in the 'Receipt and Payment Accounts' report available at https://www.pmcares.gov.in/en/web/page/about_us."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How will a formal donation receipt be issued to the donors?",
      "Response": "Donors can download receipts from the ‘Print Receipt’ section on the PM CARES portal after completing the transaction. The process and timeline vary by the mode of transaction, taking up to 7 days for some payment methods."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is there any transaction charge for online payment?",
      "Response": "No transaction charges are levied by the PM CARES Fund, but some banks may charge net-banking transaction fees."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who issues the certificate for claiming deductions under Section 80(G)?",
      "Response": "The Drawing and Disbursing Officer (DDO) / Employer issues the certificate for employees' donations to claim deductions under Section 80(G) of the Income Tax Act, 1961."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who audits the PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "The Fund is audited by M/s SARC & Associates, Chartered Accountants, New Delhi, appointed for three years starting April 23, 2020."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is the statutory period for auditing the accounts?",
      "Response": "There is no statutory period prescribed under the Income Tax Act; however, the audit is conducted at the end of the financial year."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is Foreign Donation accepted in PM CARES Fund?",
      "Response": "Yes, foreign donations are accepted and are exempt from the provisions of the Foreign Contribution (Regulation) Act, 2010. Donations can be made via foreign credit/debit cards or through Wire Transfer/SWIFT via the PM CARES Fund portal."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is Social Stock Exchange (SSE)?",
      "Response": "SSE is a platform that allows social enterprises and voluntary organizations to raise funds from the public."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is a Social Enterprise in the context of Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "A Social Enterprise is an entity that focuses on social objectives as its primary purpose and aims to achieve measurable social impact."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the minimum reporting standards mandated for Social Enterprises?",
      "Response": "Social Enterprises must adhere to minimum reporting standards, including annual impact reports and financial statements."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Which Social Enterprises are not eligible to get registered or raise funds through Social Stock Exchange/Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Social Enterprises involved in activities not related to social objectives or that violate legal guidelines are not eligible."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is a Not-for-profit organization in the context of Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "It is an organization that operates for charitable purposes and does not distribute profits to shareholders."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is a for profit social enterprise in the context of Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "A for-profit social enterprise focuses on generating profits while pursuing social or environmental objectives."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the ways in which a Not-for-profit organization can raise funds through Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Not-for-profit organizations can raise funds through donations, grants, and issuing Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is it mandatory for a Not-for-profit organization to register in order to raise funds through Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Yes, registration is mandatory for not-for-profit organizations to raise funds through SSE."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What are the criteria for registration on Social Stock Exchange in respect of Not-for-profit organizations?",
      "Response": "Criteria include being in operation for at least three years, having a valid PAN, and being registered on the NGO Darpan portal."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is it mandatory for the Not-for-Profit Organizations registered with Social Stock Exchange to seek listing?",
      "Response": "No, it is not mandatory for registered not-for-profit organizations to seek listing immediately."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What structured finance product is available for Not-for-Profit Organizations through social stock exchange mechanism?",
      "Response": "Not-for-Profit Organizations can issue Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is it mandatory to register for profit social enterprises in order to raise funds through Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Yes, registration is mandatory for for-profit social enterprises to raise funds through SSE."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "How can a for profit social enterprise raise funds through Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "For-profit social enterprises can raise funds by issuing equity, debt, or other financial instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Whether retail investors can invest in securities issued by Social Enterprises in the Social Stock Exchange Platform?",
      "Response": "Yes, retail investors can invest in securities issued by social enterprises on the SSE platform."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Can a For-Profit Organization issue Equity Shares to an Alternative Investment Fund?",
      "Response": "Yes, for-profit organizations can issue equity shares to Alternative Investment Funds (AIFs)."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Will I qualify for registration if 67% of my activities last year were in one or more items from the list of eligible activities, but my immediately preceding 3-year average is below 67%?",
      "Response": "No, the eligibility criteria require that the 67% threshold be met on an average basis over the preceding three years."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Will an NPO promoted by the promoters of a body corporate be eligible to apply?",
      "Response": "Yes, an NPO promoted by the promoters of a body corporate can apply, provided it meets the other eligibility criteria."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Whether an NPO needs to be in operations for 3 years before registering on the Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Yes, an NPO must have been in operation for at least three years before registering on the SSE."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What proof is needed to demonstrate that the NPO has been in operation for 3 years?",
      "Response": "Proof includes financial statements, annual reports, and other documents demonstrating continuous operation."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Can an NPO that is not registered on the NGO Darpan portal register on the Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "No, registration on the NGO Darpan portal is a prerequisite for SSE registration."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who will certify the documents that are needed to be submitted for registration of an NPO?",
      "Response": "The documents must be certified by a Chartered Accountant or a Company Secretary."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "If an NPO registers on the SSE, will they have to follow all the compliances even if they do not list any instruments on it?",
      "Response": "Yes, registered NPOs must follow all compliance requirements, regardless of whether they list any instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is this meant for Indian entities only or international NPOs can also get registered?",
      "Response": "The SSE is primarily for Indian entities, but international NPOs can register if they meet the criteria."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "If any Corporate is promoting one NPO through formation of a Formal Organization and then wants to register the NPO on the SSE, is it permitted?",
      "Response": "Yes, it is permitted as long as the NPO meets all the required criteria for SSE registration."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Will it be possible for an NPO to renew the registration after a year if they have not raised any money in the previous year through SSE?",
      "Response": "Yes, an NPO can renew its registration even if it has not raised funds in the previous year."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Suppose, we get registered as a SE, and while moving forward if at any point we fail to follow any guidelines. What would be the potential repercussions?",
      "Response": "Non-compliance with guidelines can lead to penalties, suspension, or deregistration from the SSE."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Are For-profit organizations eligible to issue Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments for raising funds?",
      "Response": "No, only Not-for-Profit Organizations are eligible to issue Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Which Not for Profit Organizations are eligible to issue Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments?",
      "Response": "Eligible NPOs include those engaged in social activities and meeting SSE's criteria."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Can Not-for-Profit Organizations make private issuance of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments?",
      "Response": "Yes, NPOs can make private issuances of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is the procedure for public issuance of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments by a Not-for-Profit Organization?",
      "Response": "Public issuance involves submitting an offer document to SSE, getting approvals, and complying with disclosure norms."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Can Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments be issued in physical form?",
      "Response": "No, Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments must be issued in dematerialized form."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is there any limit for issue size of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments?",
      "Response": "The issue size limits are subject to regulations set by the SSE and market conditions."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is the minimum subscription required to be achieved for successful issue of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments?",
      "Response": "The minimum subscription requirement is specified in the offer document and regulated by SSE norms."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Can a Social Enterprise terminate the listing of Zero Coupon Zero Principal Instruments from Social Stock Exchange?",
      "Response": "Yes, a Social Enterprise can terminate the listing subject to compliance with SSE regulations."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Are instruments listed by Social Enterprises available for trading in secondary market?",
      "Response": "Yes, listed instruments are available for trading in the secondary market."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is Social Audit?",
      "Response": "Social Audit is an evaluation process to assess the social impact and performance of an organization."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "What is a Social Audit Firm?",
      "Response": "A Social Audit Firm is an entity authorized to conduct social audits and certify the impact of social enterprises."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Who can act as Social Auditor?",
      "Response": "A Social Auditor is a certified professional or firm approved by the SSE to conduct social audits."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is there any Lock-in or minimum period between registration of any NPO and raising of funds from the market?",
      "Response": "Yes, there might be a lock-in period as prescribed by SSE regulations."
    },
    {
      "Prompt": "Is a merchant banker required to be appointed for preparing the draft fund – raising document?",
      "Response": "Yes, appointing a merchant banker is required for preparing the draft fundraising document."
    }
  ]